

Mobile: +81-80-8120-8225 Email: frevolous@gmail.com

Web Resume: SC

SANDIP CHAUDHARY

Career objective

To have a growth oriented and challenging career, where I can contribute my knowledge and skills to the organization and enhance my experience through teamwork.

Academic Qualification

- ★ BE. in Mechanical Engineering from Tribhuvan University, Nepal with First Division under Full Scholarship Merit-list quota.
- ★ Registered Engineer Nepal Engineering Council
- ★ PG Diploma in Piping Design Engineering; by Harpreet Singh, Udemy.
- ★ Expert in Piping Support Design in Industrial Piping; by SC Vasudevan, Udemy.
- ★ An entire MBA in one course; by Chris Haroun, Udemy
- ★ Project Management Foundations, by Bonnie Biafore, Linkedin Learning.
- ★ Sustainability for Design, Construction & Manufacturing, by Fulya Kocak Gin, Linkedin Learning.
- ★ Construction Management, Planning and Scheduling, by Jim Rogers, Linkedin Learning.
- ★ Becoming an Ally to All, by Kenji Yoshino, Linkedin Learning.
- ★ Occupational Safety and Health, by Jim Rogers, Linkedin Learning

Experiences

Site Supervisor, CCIFJ, Japan for Boccard, France – since October 2021 till now.

Reporting to Project Manager – LION PJ, an Oikos extension project for DANONE Japan, Tatebayashi Factory. Presentation of advancement, implementation of change, TO DO tasks, intervention update.

Site supervision, audit and workforce management (Two mechanical & one electrical subcontractors)

Planned v/s actual schedule (Request and addition of manpower in construction teams depending upon the progress of the workload in daily basis/ area basis).

Material requirement forecast, procurement and delivery management.

Occupational health, safety & risk assessment; and enforcement, compliance with best practices in company. Equipment and instrumentation orientation, piping arrangement and connection regard to operability, maintenance-space and accessibility.

Process control parameters-based requirements and utility piping design modifications managed with close contact with the Client-Manager.

Pneumatic & Hydrostatic pressure test to confirm the leakage, I/O test to confirm equipment functionality, Visual inspection, Endoscopy in pigging line and Site acceptance test (SAT) during commissioning. Onsite policies, procedures and standards maintained and ensured all documentation and practices.

Mechanical scope: - Onsite arrangement for installation of yoghurt and product storage tanks (two 50 m³ tanks).

Mechanical scope: Onsite arrangement for installation of yoghurt and product storage tanks (two 50 m³ tanks and one 25 m³ tank) with hopper, ladder and platform, Installation of Cup making, Fruit & product(Oikos) Filling & Packaging machine and palletizer robots, Thermizer unit (Plate heat exchanger, process skid, holding unit and pumps), Water, Air and Steam filtration skids, Cooler unit (PHE, Chilled water tank, process skid and pump), PCM pumps for filler machine, Separator Unit (Separator machine, Process skid and CIP skid), Chemical tanks (15 m³ Caustic soda and 10 m³ Nitric Acid) meant for the supply of concentrate for the purpose of CIP, Valve cluster modification for mix-proof sanitary valves and CIP station capacity extension.

Weld clean – Chemical pickling HNO₃ & Chlorinated water (sodium hypochlorite + water), weld with orbital welding machine particularly for pigging line(other TIG/shop). Insulation with Rockwool (<250°C, conductivity low, fire resistant) for Hot service & Neoma-form or phenolic resin (Thermal conductivity-0.02, fire resistant)/ polyurethane alternative for Cold service line, Installation and arrangement assisted with use of crane for tanks, hoist for lifting to second floor, forklift, hydraulic press, Scaffolding & scissor lift for work at height.

- a. Piping lines involved Pasteurizer line, Calamity cooler line, Thermizer line, Cooler line, Filler line, Fruit line from fruit station, CIP supply line, CIP return line, SIP/sterilisation line for filler, Utility supply line (Compressed air, water, steam), Filtered (air, water) and Cullinary steam.
- b. Process parameters concerned Slope for product line to be 2%, flow rate for CIP to be 35m³/hr, Steam pressure range to be 2~6 bar consequently temperature to be 140°C~160°C, Compressed air pressure to be 5 bar, Well-water to be 4 bar.

Electrical & automation scope: — Panel & cabinet wiring corresponding to each skid with PLC setup, inverter setup, master and slave arrangement as per electrical diagram, communication network with optical fiber for SCADA loop, profibus, profinet & ethernet for communication in between the panels, ASI and orange cable for communication with equipment to the panel, ASI addressing to the equipment, [(Pressure, Temperature and Level) sensors/ transmitters, proximity switch, conductivity meter, modulating valve, solenoid valve, pump motor & heater coil] wiring and HMI use.

Electrical loop involved – Profinet loop, Profibus loop, Ethernet loop and Optical fiber loop.

Plant Design Engineer, FES Holdings – August 2020 ~ Sept 2021.

Reporting to Piping Lead; (for FEED, EPC PJs)

Pipe Support Drawing, ISO Drawing, 3D Modelling and Site-visit (Confirmation of Spool Drawing).

Software Used: AutoCAD for 2D drafting, PDMS, E3D & AutoCAD Plant 3D for 3D Modelling,

Navisworks for Model Review, and Auto-PIPE for Thermal Stress Analysis.

Project Involved: AGC Semi Chemical Company NAOH Production Plant, Chigasaki, Japan.
Sony Nagasaki Semiconductor Plant Project and Himeji Natural Gas Plant Project for Organo Corporation, Japan.

Piping Engineer, JCON, Singapore for JGC Group (Global EPC Contractor) – July 2018 ~ May 2020 Reporting to Team Lead/Piping Lead Engineer; (for FEED, EPC PJs)

Overall Material Handling, using (P&ID, FDCN, Line Index, ISO sketch, Plot plan, ASME & ASTM standards for Dimension & Material STD.), MTO of Piping Bulk (Valve, Pipe, Fittings, Flanges, Nut & Bolts), Specialty, Instrument, Pipe Support [{Springs, SLP, VIP, Cold Shoe, Cold Ins Block, Clamp Shoe}, Trunnion/stanchion/Drum/Removable stool, Braces, etc.], BMBQ Calculation using software, KPI & chart preparation, RML (for BO & PO) creation, 3D modelling monitoring for ISO check via NAVIS, Dimension control activities, General Arrangement Drawing review, MTO Quantity estimation based on historical data.

Software Used: [AutoCAD for 2D drafting (Fluent), Navisworks (Fluent), Macslite (BMBQ Calculation), PTM (Historical Data Handling), JPSS2 (Pipe Support BM Calculation), J-STRESS (Stress Calculation Database), CAESAR II only for support MTO, J-DMS (Check & Update General Arrangement Drawings), Excel (Advanced functions, charts & power query)

Project Involved:

- 1. LNG Canada LNG Processing and Storage Facility
- 2. JTB, Indonesia Sulphuric Acid Plant
- 3. Kuraray ES, Thailand Ethylene Production Plant

Regional Service Engineer, Jagdamba Motors (a distributor of **TVS Motors**, India) Feb 2017~June 2018. Reporting to Regional Manager

Routine supervision, monitoring and upgrading of the Region regarding workstations, condition of service standards, infrastructures conditions update and technical as well product training to the manpower and dealer viability calculation.

Gap analysis as per the Order vs Dispatch of Spare parts at the dealer end. Customer care department functioning monitoring and evaluation.

Monthly performance report preparation including Service report; regarding service inflow, parts & lube consumption for a month; & CCD report regarding customer satisfaction and dissatisfaction data analysis. Report preparation through the extensive use of Excel and it's add-ins.

Earned Training on (Eye CAD & P-DMS) software and taught from Aug 2017 to Oct 2017 at **TOWA Engineering Nepal Pvt. Ltd.**

Has learnt basic 3D drafting tools of Eye-CAD & P-DMS.

Drafted 3D Chemical Plant (Plant area, Structures, Beams, Floor, Staircase, Ladder, Equipment like Tank, Heat exchanger, Pump insertion in Drawing, Piping (flange, valve and joint types and uses in drawing), Ducts, etc.

Worked as Engineering Intern for **Project-A**; from March 2017 to Aug 2017.

Gathered data from automobile dealers from all over Nepal. Analyzed as per the Policy Deployment Plan, summarized and stored.

Make a monthly performance report regarding total sales of spares parts, lube, labor charge for per day vehicle inflow and present it to the Chief.

President: Campus Student Welfare Committee.

Served for a term of 1 year from 2015 to 2016.

Organized Blood donation program, cultural fest and technical training (AutoCAD, SolidWorks, Office package, Email & Internet).

Research on Design, Development & Demonstration of RC-planes.

Reviewed article of Australian scholar, Danise John, John Danise Model of Aircraft Design.

Reviewed project report of N. Krishnamurthy of IIT, Mumbai (rcbuildfly.weebly.com).

Gathered information from (www.instructables.com, NASA page, etc.)

As a Team Leader of the group of 5 members; fabricated a prototype Remote Controlled (RC) plane with Balsa Wood & Thermo-cole.

Used 30A Electronic Speed Controller, 6x4 steel propeller, 1500kv Brushless Motor, 220g 2200mAh Li-Po Battery, Coreless servos & Fly-sky 8ch Transmitter & Receiver set.

Also, readymade ECU (Electronic Control Unit) & BEC (Battery Elimination Circuit) was used. Model Design aided through SolidWorks.

Software proficiency

- ✓ Plant Design Software known: AutoCAD, Eye-CAD (Japanese Version), P-DMS, E3D, AutoCAD Plant 3D, SolidWorks, Navis-Works, Matterport, Auto-PIPE, CAESAR II
- ✔ Programming skill: C Programming, PowerBI & PowerQuery, Python & Machine Learning, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap library, React, JavaScript, JQuery, PHP, SQL, MongoDB, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Deploy with Heroku, RESTful API, Git & Github version control.
- ✓ Office suite: MS-office [Excel (Power-BI & Power Query)] & MS-Project
- ✓ Multimedia Skills (Adobe Photoshop, Movie maker)

Training

- 1. Organization: Korean International Cultural Agency (KOICA)
- ♦ Duration: 5 months
- Knowledge Gained: Learnt about various software including AutoCAD 2007, Adobe Photoshop, Movie maker, MS-Office.
- 2. Organization: Small & Cottage Industry Training Center
- Duration: 3 months
- ❖ Knowledge Gained: Repair & Maintenance of 2 wheelers
- 3. Organization: Small & Cottage Industry Training Center
- Duration: 7 days
- ❖ Knowledge Attained: Entrepreneurship
- 4. Organization: Udemy Online Academy
- ❖ Title: Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp
- ❖ Title: AutoCAD Plant 3D
- ❖ Title: Aveva E3D

Extra-curricular activities

Participated and won prizes in English essay & Drawing competition at school level.

Active participant of Marathon & Active blood donor.

Possess both 2 & 4 wheelers Driving License [Nepali License].

Personal Trait

Co-operative and keen observer Quick Learner (Familiar with navigating support from Google and Youtube)

Hobbies

Programming.
Participating in Athletic Events and Cooking.
Playing Table tennis

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 15.10.1993

Gender: Male

Marital status: Married

Languages Known: [Nepali, English, Japanese (N3), Maithili and Hindi] (Read and Write)

Nationality: Nepali

Summary

• Engineer-Observe, identify, analyze and apply on the basis of Physics of matter and; solution in relation to the socio-economic aspects.

• Keen Observing Capability is something natural in me that enables me to stand out among groups. Example: I could easily point out defects in drawing; even in real life, at the working space, access ways, and

staircase landing space, etc. as per the experience until now.
Along-with, the strong Enthusiasm in updating knowledge with Latest Technology trends in automation, learning & lifestyle.

Example: Started learning Python & Power-BI after knowing about their use in data handling routine work automation & visualization. Similarly, PG Diploma in Piping Design, MBA and so on.

I hereby declare that all the details furnished here are true to the best of my knowledge.

Best Regards, Chaudhary, Sandip